Well, the first and probably easiest
place to host is GitHub since we've
already learned how to store our code
there. So, here I have the die um
what's it called? The die roller app.
And I'll just bring it over into this
window in just a second. Okay, here is
the die roller app. You can click roll
the die. You can freeze a die and it
won't roll again. Um this is the
solution code. Um so I'm going to push
it up to GitHub. So to do that, I'm
going to open up GitHub desktop and I'm
going to make the commit. So I'm going
to say my solution
and I'll say getting ready to deploy.
So we'll commit that and then we'll
publish this branch. I am on the deploy
branch. So publish the branch. Hopefully
all of this looks pretty much like the
GitHub videos. All right.
So now I could preview the poll request,
but what I'm going to do is I'm going to
click view on GitHub [snorts] and that
opens up
this page right here. So you could merge
your code in with the main branch. I'm
not going to so that people can keep
forking this repository if they need for
the previous videos. Um, so I'm going to
leave it unmerged. But what I'm going to
do is I'm going to come over here to
settings. When I click on settings, I'm
going to scroll down on this lefth hand
panel until I get to the word pages.
Then I'm going to click on pages.
Then it says it's designed to host
personal, organizational, or project
pages from a GitHub repository. And then
use source. We're going to say deploy
from a branch. What that means is it
will take your code off of a branch and
it will make it publicly accessible the
running website. So which branch do you
want to do? Well, if you merge your code
in with main, then you'll click main. I
put mine on deploy, so I'm going to say
deploy. And then it says, what folder do
you want to deploy from? Do you want to
deploy from root or docs? What it's
going to be looking for is it's going to
be looking for your index.html file. So
if we come back over to our Visual
Studio Code, if we look at what we
pushed up, we can see that in our main
folder is index.html. And so because
it's in our main folder, we're going to
want to leave this as root. Then you're
going to hit save.
And now it says your GitHub pages source
is saved. And if you come over to your
code
um and we'll reload this page. And
actually I do think we need to switch
this over to the deploy branch. So it
was on main, we changed over to deploy.
You can see this pending dot here. What
that means is your website is presently
deploying and it will change to a green
check mark when it's done. That does
take a few minutes. So I am going to
pause the video until we get there.
Okay. So, sometimes you'll have to
reload it to get this green check mark.
Um, and I did have to reload it. Um, but
you can see it took probably about four
minutes at least according to GitHub.
Um, four minutes for this to happen. So,
now that you've got the green check
mark, what you're going to want to do,
um, is you can see you've got a
deployment to GitHub pages. Um, and you
can go to settings
and click on pages again. And here your
site is live. And so if you visit this
website, you can see tada. And if you
look up at the top tab, you can see it's
https double slash probably your github
username.github.iothename
of your repository. And this website is
live, so anyone could go visit it. Um,
and it works exactly like it did before.
So we could freeze this dice and roll
all the others. Could freeze some more
dice.
And it works exactly like it did on our
local computer, but now it's deployed.
And that means that your code that was
trapped on your computer before is now
publicly accessible for anyone out there
to get to. And that's how you deploy on
GitHub pages.